# Rashmi Desai

™ rash.desai09@gmail.com

+91-9845477033

Pangalore, India

in linkedin.com/in/rashmi-desai

rashmidesai09

# **S** Key Skills

Programming Languages COBOL, SAS, SQL, Python

**Relational Databases** *IBM DB2, PostgreSQL, MySQL* 

**Data Management** 

Legacy Data Migration, ETL, Data Modelling, Analysis, Reporting and Visualization

#### **Software and Tools**

Power BI, Excel, IBM IDZ, Visual Studio, Git & GitHub, ServiceNow, Sharepoint

# **Cloud Computing** *Microsoft Azure*

**Methodologies** *Agile, Waterfall, PPQA* 

## Projects

# **Building a CI/CD pipeline in Azure** ☑ Sep 2022 – Oct 2022

- Created a CI/CD pipeline in Azure from scratch for ML application implemented with sklearn and flask
- Predicted Boston's house price using the application

# Azure Data Integration Pipelines for NYC Payroll Data ☑

Aug 2022 - Sep 2022

- Loaded data residing on Azure Data Lake Gen2 into Azure Synapse Analytics for processing
- Automated data pipelines using Azure Data Factory and monitored the same for efficient operation

### Data Analysis Projects 🛚

May 2022 - Jun 2022

- Performed EDA, Descriptive statistics, and Anomaly detection for sales data in Microsoft Excel
- Analyzed Titanic dataset from Kaggle using SQL with Python Pandas
  Created report for ForestQuery into
- Created report for ForestQuery into Global Deforestation using SQL
- Conducted Rewards credit card data analysis using Python Pandas
- Prepared dashboard using Power BI for Sales data insights

## **Summary**

Thorough and Meticulous data professional having 9+ years of experience in Data Analytics/Engineering, Mainframe Application Development and Modernization. Empowering stakeholders to make data-driven decisions with the ability to build and lead teams of talented professionals to develop valuable solutions that meet business objectives.

### **Education**

## Data Engineer for Shell (IDA)

*Udacity Nanodegree Program* Jun 2022 – Nov 2022

### **B.E - Electrical and Electronics Engineering**

K.L.E Institute of Technology, VTU

Sep 2008 - Sep 2012

• Grade - First Class with Distinction

# **Work Experience**

### **Team Lead**

SLK Software Pvt. Ltd, Client: U.S. Banking & Payments Business Units Apr 2021 – Oct 2022

- Supported consumer credit cards and rewards products for the Bank in all phases of the product life-cycle
- Lead 8+ members team in the transformation of traditional bill payments and processing solutions
- Researched data for driving RFI/RFPs, creation of a roadmap for role progression, attrition trend analysis, CSAT rating analysis, publishing technical newsletters

#### **Data Analyst**

SLK Software Pvt. Ltd, Client: U.S. Banking & Payments Business Units Apr 2019 – Jul 2020

- Automated Recurring SOP activities by upgrading the traditional data extraction utilities into SAS procedures leading to saving 70% of the time and manual effort
- Accomplished clean-up of 1280k inactive rewards credit cards in the loyalty program partner's database; leading to cost savings for the Bank
- Developed RCA reports addressing problems such as data syncing with third-party vendors, audit errors, etc. resolved 25% of customer complaints

#### **Mainframe Senior Developer**

SLK Software Pvt. Ltd, Client : Super Regional Bank of U.S Jan 2015 – Mar 2019

- Delivered 5 major programs EMV chip cards technology, Bankruptcy reconciliation, Introducing Multi-cards for the bank, Secured card Graduation and Product simplification
- Authored system maintenance technical documents for servicing applications improving the learning curve of new team members by 25%

#### **Mainframe Developer**

Atos Syntel, Client : Humana Inc. , American Health Insurance company Dec 2012 – Dec 2014

- Supported the end-to-end project life cycle for the MetaVance claims application
- Developed reports for error handling and reducing defects leading to an 85% improvement in the quality of deliverables

# **Certifications**

### Lean Six Sigma Green Belt

Issuer: NIQC International

## **AWS Cloud Quest: Cloud Practitioner**

Issuer: Amazon Web Services Training and Certification